Hello and welcome to English learning
hub.
English listening test designed for A1
learners.
This test consists of 30 questions which
are divided into six parts. I will give
you a short instruction at the beginning
of each part.
Before we get started, take a pen and
paper so you can take notes while
listening.
Are you ready? Let's get started.
Part one. Listen to Martin talking about
his family photos and take notes.
These are great photos. Who's the girl
in this one?
That's Sophie. She's my little sister.
How many sisters do you have?
Two. That's my other sister, Hannah.
She's very pretty. How old is she?
28. She teaches English in India.
Do you see her often?
Not really. She comes home once or twice
a year. This is her daughter, Kelly.
She's only three. And that's her
husband, Peter. He's a teacher, too.
Is that woman your mother?
No, that's Barbara. She's my dad's
sister. She's really nice. This is my
mom.
What does she do?
She's a lawyer. This is all of the
family at Christmas. That's Barbara's
husband, Mark. And that's their son,
Donald. He's the same age as me, but I
don't like him. He's a bank manager.
Is that girl one of your cousins?
No, that's Jane. She's my ex-girlfriend.
Choose the correct option.
[Music]
Na.
Hey. Hey.
Heat. Heat.
[Music]
Part two. Listen to five conversations
and take notes.
[Laughter]
What do you usually have for breakfast,
Kate?
Oh, I hardly ever have time for
breakfast at home. I always get up late.
I take the train to work and I usually
buy a sandwich and a cup of coffee from
a little cafe near the train station. I
have them at my desk.
Do you often go out in the evenings,
Mary? No, I'm afraid my social life
isn't very exciting. I usually get home
and take a shower. Then I make dinner.
After dinner, I read a book. I get up at
6:00 a.m., so I'm always in bed at
10:00.
Where do your parents live, John?
In a small town in Western
Massachusetts.
How often do you visit them?
Not very often. About once every four
months. It takes around 4 hours to get
there by train and the tickets are very
expensive. I usually go up for mom's
birthday and for dad's birthday and I
always go home for Christmas.
Do you work on the weekend, Linda?
No, my weekends are for relaxing. On
Saturday morning, I have a long bath.
After lunch, I meet my best friend,
Annie, and we go shopping together. We
usually buy clothes or CDs. In the
evening, I go out with my boyfriend. We
usually have dinner in a restaurant, but
sometimes we go to the movies.
Do you get up early, Edward?
Not every day. I get up at 5:00 during
the week because I have a long drive to
work. And on Saturdays, I sometimes get
up at 8:00 and go to the gym, but I
don't do that very often. Usually, I
stay in bed until around 9:00. What
about you? Oh, I have three children. I
always get up early.
Choose the correct option.
[Music]
down.
Can
you
feel?
[Music]
Part three. Steve is looking for a
summer job. Listen to the interview.
Come in and take a seat, Steve.
Thank you.
So, you're looking for a summer job? Do
you have any hotel experience?
I'm afraid not. My parents have a shop
and I sometimes help out when they're
busy.
Well, a lot of our visitors don't speak
English. Can you speak any other
languages?
My parents are from Spain, so my Spanish
is very good, and I know some French.
Okay, good. What about German?
I know a few words, but I can't speak it
very well.
Now, we need people who can drive
because the hotel is a long way from the
town and there aren't any buses.
Well, I can drive, but I don't have a
car. I want a summer job, so I can buy
one. But it's okay because I have a
motorcycle.
That's great. What about computers? Can
you use a computer?
Yes, I'm very good with computers. I'm
studying computing in college. Once a
week, we have Italian food and music
night for our visitors. Can you sing or
play a musical instrument?
Well, I know some Italian songs, but my
girlfriend says that I'm not a very good
singer, but I can play the guitar quite
well, and I'm a very good dancer. I know
lots of Italian dances.
Great. Well, thanks very much for coming
here. We'll call you next week about the
job.
Choose the correct answer.
[Music]
Hey.
Part four. Listen to five people talking
about the weather.
New York is so cold.
Well, it is winter. What's the weather
like in Australia today? It's summer
now, so it's really hot and sunny. It
hardly ever rains and you can go to the
beach every day.
What do you usually do when the sun's
shining, Lisa?
Well, I live a long way from the coast,
so I don't go to the beach. There's a
park downtown, but I prefer to go there
when it's cold and there aren't a lot of
people around. When the weather's good,
I usually go down to the river and relax
with a book. Do you go shopping?
No, I never go shopping when it's hot.
Our shopping center doesn't have air
conditioning.
No, it's over to Karen Brown for the
weather forecast.
It's good news for New England today.
It's a cold and windy day, but you don't
need an umbrella. Temperatures are
between 40 and 50°, so wear warm
clothes.
Be careful when you drive home.
Why? The roads aren't dangerous. It
isn't raining and there's no ice on the
road.
It's sometimes quite foggy here at night
and you can't see the road.
Oh, right. Thanks for telling me.
What's your favorite season, Jack?
That's a good question. It isn't summer.
A lot of people like hot weather, but I
don't. Spring and fall are too
changeable. One minute you need
sunglasses, the next minute you need an
umbrella. I think winter is my favorite
time of year because it snows and I can
ski every day.
[Music]
Heat. Heat.
[Laughter]
What date is it, Jennifer? November
25th. Why? Only 30 shopping days until
Christmas. Oh, no. I hate shopping. And
shopping at Christmas is really bad. I
don't like buying presents for people
because I never know what to buy.
Really? I love it. And Christmas is my
favorite time of the year. I love seeing
my family on Christmas day and opening
my Christmas presents. What about the
dark nights and the cold weather? I
don't mind them. And it's great when it
snows.
It hardly ever snows in Baltimore at
Christmas. Maybe, but my parents live in
Vermont and it always snows there.
I prefer summer. The weather's nice and
I can do lots of things. I like getting
up early and going for a run before
everyone wakes up. You can't do that in
winter. It's so dark in the morning. I
like summer, too. My birthday's on the
21st of June, the first day of summer,
and I usually go out after work with my
friends. And I love Labor Day at the
beginning of September because we have a
day off work and lots of stores open on
public holidays.
[Music]
Hello. 5552406.
Hi. Is Laura there?
No, I'm sorry. She's taking a shower.
Can you give her a message? This is her
cousin Amy. She has my laptop and I need
it for work.
Sarah, what's Paul's number?
I don't know. Oh, here you are. Use my
cell phone. His number is on there. Find
his name and press the button.
Thanks.
Hello. Paul speaking.
Hi, Paul. It's Rebecca. Do you want to
come to a party tomorrow?
Hello.
Hello, Sandra. It's David.
Air. There's no Sandra here.
Oh, dear. What number is this?
It's 802558956.
I'm sorry. It's the wrong number.
Who are you calling? Patricia.
Michelle.
Why are you calling her? You see her
every day at work.
I know, but there's a party at her house
tomorrow and I don't know what time it
starts.
Oh, can I come with you?
What's that noise? What noise? That
sound? I don't know. Oh, it's my phone.
It's new.
Hello. Hello. Oh, there's no one there.
What's that? I think you have a message.
[Music]
Heat.
Heat. Heat.
[Music]
Heat. Hey, heat. Hey, heat.
Heat. Heat. N.
[Music]
[Applause]